# **CHRISTINE** SCHAT7

cmschatz@gmail.com

www.christineschatz.com

**\** 323-828-8487

**♀** Easton, PA

in /christineschatz

ChristineSchatz

I truly enjoy problem solving. Whether it's figuring out how an app's data should be structured or how a user experience should be designed, I'm energized by crafting creative solutions to problems. I'm drawn to good people who enjoy sharing ideas and making a difference.

### Skills

#### **LANGUAGES**

Ruby

JavaScript

Java

PHP

Scala

#### FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES

Rails

Laravel

#### **TESTING**

RSpec

Capybara

#### **FRONT END**

HTML5

CSS3

Sass

jQuery

React Riot

#### **METHODOLOGIES**

Object-oriented design

Agile

#### DATABASE

ActiveRecord

PostgreSQL

SQL

#### DEVOPS

Docker

Vagrant

### **Employment**

PetFlow

Junior Full Stack Engineer

- Used JavaScript, riot.js, jQuery to implement front end features
- Used PHP (Laravel) on the backend
- Wrote unit tests
- Refactored parts of a large codebase

ValuePenguin

Junior Developer (Contract)

New York NY Oct 2015 to Dec 2015

New York, NY

Jan 2016 to Current

- Built interactive tools such as a financial calculator Used JavaScript, React, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, and Sass to build features on the front end
- Wrote Scala and PHP to customize data on the back end
- Developed in Docker containers

Lafayette College Coordinator - IDEAL Center & Office of Off-Campus Education

Easton, PA Jul 2013 to Jun 2015

- Developed the footprints for an entrepreneurship initiative
- Implemented JavaScript, HTML & CSS to departmental website
- Worked with external partners & alumni to curate entrepreneurship-focused events

East Greenville, PA Knoll Jan 2013 to Jun 2013

- Project Analyst
  - Compiled and analyzed data from supply chain work streams
  - · Created master project plan using project management software

# **Projects**

#### THE <HIVE>

A social networking site for software developers looking to collaborate on a side project. Users can coordinate meetups using an in-app messaging system. Users can also search for a project by any given city or zip code.

- Played a large role in implementing the Google Geocoding API to render location results.
- Designed the splash page
- Built a portion of the CRUD features for projects
- Implemented AJAX for smoother data loading

Stack: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Materialize, Sass

URL: https://code-hive.herokuapp.com

#### **EMOTIONAL BAGGAGE CHECK IOS APP**

The iOS app version of the popular desktop site Emotional Baggage Check. Users can post "baggage" anonymously as well as receive an anonymous response.

- · Used Swift and Parse API as a backend
- Utilized MVC design pattern, divide and conquer strategies, and debugging tools throughout development

Stack: Swift, Objective-C, Parse

### **Education**

Northampton Community College A.S. Computer Science 2015 Dean's List, GPA: 3.9

Dev Bootcamp Web Development 2015

University of California, San Diego B.A. Visual Arts: Media 2008 Graduated with Honors

# Activities

The Loop Founder & Writer

Music blogger for popular. Hype-Machine ranked music blog "The Loop." I work with PR agents and artists to feature independent music. I'm also a music reviewer for Fluence.io

Coders > Cancer Hackathon · Developer

Collaborated on a team of 4 to develop Ladybug, a text messaging system that reminds women to do their monthly self breast exam. Used Ruby on Rails and HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery to design the splash page

### Awards

Style of Sound Best Music Blog Award Awarded ranking in Style of Sound's "Most Influential Music Blogs of 2014" list